Colin R. Brine

Software Engineer

Email: brinec@gmail.com - Phone: (978) 798-9973 - Location: New England and Open to Relocation
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brinec/ - Portfolio: https://brinecr.github.io/ - GitHub: https://github.com/brinecr

Summary

I am an enthusiastic software engineer with a history in the IT and technical support fields. Having worked in a myriad of positions as the pivot between engineers and customers it has helped me build a holistic perspective on project-based environments. I love to learn and challenge myself.

Technical Toolset

Linux (Ubuntu), Mac, Windows, Javascript, Python, MongoDB, Django, SQL (PostgreSQL), Node.js, Express, React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS/SASS, Markup, jQuery, Wireframes, User Stories, AJAX, Axios, bcrypt, Cors, Socket.io, Agile, Scrum

Work Experience

Software Engineering Immersive Fellow - General Assembly

April 2020 - June 2020

480+ hours of coursework; individual and team based

Four full-stack projects with current technologies in software development:

- Character Creation Tool SPA + API Solo full-stack application project highlighting a React/Javascript front-end with a custom build Django/Python back-end. This allows you to log in, create a character, view all of your characters and edit their health attributes. Serving as a foundation for a future monster battling platform.
- Project Stardust Chat SPA + API Group full-stack application project highlighting a React/Javascript front-end w/ Express/Javascript API back-end w/ sockets.io and pair programming. This includes an auth section, chat section, and updatable user profile.
- Pet Sharing SPA +API Solo full-stack application project w/ Javascript, Handlebars, jQuery, HTML/SASS front-end and Express API back-end. This has an auth section, then you can add and share your pets. You could also see all pets but only edit your own. It was my first project doing both the front and back end programming.
- Tic-Tac-Toe SPA Solo front-end project creating a game board and logic, creating a SPA, and integrating with an existing API. This was my first project utilizing Javascript, HTML, jQuery, SASS.

IT, Technical, Product and Desktop Support

October 2012 - March 2020

Desktop Support Specialist Team Lead (temp) - Optos via The Davis Companies - Marlborough, MA

Support Engineer Level 1 - Vision Government Solutions - Hudson, MA

 ${\bf Business\ Services\ Support\ Professional\ -\ Comcast\ Business\ -\ Hudson,\ NH}$

AR Retention Specialist (temp) - Tyco SimplexGrinnell - Westminster, MA

Customer Service Representative - Destination Weddings Travel Group - Wayland, MA

Product and Technical Support Specialist II - Bose Corporation - Westborough, MA

Product and Technical Support Specialist (temp) - Bose Corporation via Randstad - Westborough, MA

- The ability to translate technical information to a non-technical audience.
- Ability to prioritize daily responsibilities and demonstrate good time management.
- Recognizes and diffuses difficult customer situations utilizing all resources, interpersonal and negotiating skills to come to resolution.
- Provides prompt resolution to customers via telephone, e-mail or chat to assist with customer inquiries and issues.

Additional Extra Experience

February 2011 - Current

Co-Founder/Event Organizer - 4orce Productions - Music/Rental/Event Company - MA, NH DJ - Bars, Clubs, Weddings, Festivals - MA, NH, ME, CT, RI, VT, NY

- Organizing events on a consistent basis in New England.
- Coordinating promotion, DJs, sound and equipment rentals.
- Handles Twitter, Facebook, and social media presence.

Education & Awards

Middlesex Community College - Associate Degree in Criminal Justice - MA Norwich University - Took coursework in Computer Security and Information Assurance - VT Eagle Scout